dyestat.com 2019-03-31

# About - Privacy Policy - Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy  
Last Revised October 22nd, 2012:

RunnerSpace / Deker Net LLC (“RunnerSpace” or “we”) operates RunnerSpace.com, Athletic.net and DyeStat. This Privacy Policy describes RunnerSpace’s use and sharing of personally identifiable information (“PII”-- your full name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, or credit card number) that Members voluntarily provide to RunnerSpace when they register (also known as “Registration PII”). The Term “User” refers to a Visitor or a Member. This Privacy Policy applies to the services offered by RunnerSpace, including any RunnerSpace-branded URL (the “RunnerSpace Website”), the RunnerSpace messaging system, the RunnerSpace application developer service and other features (for example, video embedded players, apps, personal websites, event websites, pages etc), RunnerSpace mobile services, and any other features, content, or applications offered from time to time by RunnerSpace in connection with the RunnerSpace Website (collectively, the “RunnerSpace Services”). The RunnerSpace Services are hosted in the United States.

The RunnerSpace Website is a general audience site and does not knowingly collect PII from children under 13 years of age.

From time to time RunnerSpace may modify this Privacy Policy to reflect industry initiatives or changes in the law, our PII collection and use practices, the features of the RunnerSpace Services, or technology, and such modifications shall be effective upon posting by RunnerSpace on the RunnerSpace Website. Your continued use of the RunnerSpace Services after RunnerSpace posts a revised Privacy Policy signifies your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy. It is therefore important that you review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure you are updated as to any changes. If RunnerSpace materially changes its practices regarding collection or use of your PII, your PII will continue to be governed by the Policy under which it was collected unless you have been provided notice of, and have not objected to, the change.

COLLECTION AND SUBMISSION OF PII AND NON-PII ON RUNNERSPACE

General. When RunnerSpace collects PII from you it is because you are voluntarily submitting Registration PII to us in order to register as a Member of RunnerSpace. RunnerSpace may also collect PII from you if you choose to participate in RunnerSpace Services activities like sweepstakes, contests, apps and surveys, because you want us to furnish you with products, services, newsletters, or information, or in connection with content or suggestions you submit to RunnerSpace for review.

In addition, RunnerSpace collects other non-PII including IP address, aggregate user data, and browser type. This data is used to manage and improve the RunnerSpace Services, track usage, and for security purposes.

RunnerSpace Members may also choose to provide or store non-PII information in their profiles, including but not limited to date of birth, interests, likes, follows, hobbies, lifestyle choices, events, groups and teams with whom they are affiliated (schools, companies), videos and/or pictures, blogs, news, results, private messages, bulletins or personal statements (collectively “Profile Information”). The Profile Information in a Member’s profile is provided at his or her sole discretion.

RunnerSpace Members can change their Registration PII and Profile Information at any time and can control how Visitors, other Members and RunnerSpace communicate with them by controlling their account settings, available within the “Edit Details” and "Notifications / Privacy Settings" //www.runnerspace.com/forum/index.php?app=core&module=usercp&tab=core&area=notifications portion of their RunnerSpace profile.

Cookies. Cookies are small bits of information that RunnerSpace places on your computer. RunnerSpace uses cookies to identify your Internet browser, store Users’ preferences, and determine whether you have installed the enabling software needed to access certain material on the RunnerSpace Services. Data in cookies may be read to authenticate user sessions or provide services.

Third party advertisements displayed on RunnerSpace Services may also contain cookies set by Internet advertising companies or advertisers (known as “third party cookies”). RunnerSpace does not control these third party cookies and Users of the RunnerSpace Services should check the privacy policy of the Internet advertising company or advertiser to see whether and how it uses cookies. See the “Notice” section below for more information on customized advertising on RunnerSpace. A pixel tag is a tiny image inserted in a webpage and used to record the number and types of views for that page. RunnerSpace may allow third party pixel tags to be present on RunnerSpace Services for purposes of advertising, providing services or data and statistics collection.

You can program your computer to warn you each time a cookie is being sent, block third party cookies or block all cookies. However, by blocking all cookies you may not have access to certain features on the RunnerSpace Services.

NOTICE: RUNNERSPACE WILL PROVIDE YOU WITH NOTICE ABOUT ITS PII COLLECTION PRACTICES

When you voluntarily provide PII to RunnerSpace, we will make sure you are informed about who is collecting the information, how and why the information is being collected and the types of uses RunnerSpace will make of the information to the extent it is being used in a manner that differs from what is allowed pursuant to this Privacy Policy.

At the time you provide your PII, RunnerSpace will notify you of your options regarding our use of your PII (See “Choice” below). Except as described in this Privacy Policy, RunnerSpace will not share your PII with third parties unless you have given RunnerSpace permission to do so (See “Use” below).

RunnerSpace Services may be linked to Internet sites operated by other companies. RunnerSpace Services may also carry advertisements from other companies. RunnerSpace is not responsible for the privacy practices of websites or other services operated by third parties that are linked to or integrated with the RunnerSpace Services or for the privacy practices of third party Internet advertising companies. Once you leave RunnerSpace Services via such a link, access a third party application (such as widgets, events, pages etc) or click on an advertisement, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party or advertiser site to determine, among other things, how they will handle any PII they collect from you.

RunnerSpace Services may also be linked to sites operated by companies affiliated with RunnerSpace (i.e., that are part of the RunnerSpace or Deker Net LCC: “Affiliated Companies”). Although all Affiliated Companies should generally adhere to the RunnerSpace Privacy Principles, Users who visit those Affiliated Company sites should still refer to their separate privacy policies and practices if applicable, which may differ in some respects from this Privacy Policy.

RunnerSpace may use cookies and similar tools to customize the content and advertising you receive based on the Profile Information you have provided. Profile Information you provide in structured profile fields or questions (multiple/pulldown choice questions like “Gender”, “Birthdate” etc.) (“Structured Profile Information”), "likes", "follows", "events", information you add to open-ended profile fields and questions (essay questions like “About Me,”) (“Non-Structured Profile Information”) and other non-PII about you may also be used to customize the online ads you encounter to those we believe are aligned with your interests or likes. For example, based on the events or groups you like we might display an advertisement to make sure you are advised when your favorite teams, interests or events have updates. The information used for this feature does not provide your PII or identify you as an individual to third parties. If you would like to disable advertising customization for Non-Structured Profile Information, simply leave your fields blank and un-follow content, groups etc.

Some of the advertisements that appear on RunnerSpace Services may also be delivered to you by third party Internet advertising companies. These companies utilize certain technologies to deliver advertisements and marketing messages and to collect non-PII about your visit to or use of RunnerSpace Services, including information about the ads they display, via a cookie placed on your computer that reads your IP address. To opt out of information collection by these companies, or to obtain information about the technologies they use or their own privacy policies, please click here http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ .

Third party applications (such as widgets) created by third party developers may also be available on the RunnerSpace Services. Third party applications are small bits of software, often with interactivity, that can be installed into Members’, events, pages etc profiles or shared with other Users. However, RunnerSpace does not control the third party developers, and cannot dictate their actions. When a Member engages with a third party application, that Member is interacting with the third party developer, not with RunnerSpace. RunnerSpace encourages Members not to provide PII to the third party’s application unless the Member knows the party with whom it is interacting.

CHOICE: RUNNERSPACE WILL PROVIDE YOU WITH CHOICES ABOUT THE USE OF YOUR PII

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, RunnerSpace will get your permission before we use the PII you provide to us in a way that is inconsistent with the purpose for which it was submitted or share your PII with third parties that are not affiliated with RunnerSpace.

USE: RUNNERSPACE'S USE OF PII

RunnerSpace will only use the PII you provide under this Privacy Policy in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. If RunnerSpace obtains PII from a third party, such as a business partner, our use of that information is also governed by this Privacy Policy.

In order to locate other RunnerSpace Members that you may already know in the physical or social world, RunnerSpace may allow Users to search for Members using Registration PII (i.e., full name or email address, Facebook friends and other social media outlets). RunnerSpace also allows Users to browse for certain Profile Information in order to help connect with Members (i.e., schools, teams, events and/or companies where Users may have attended or worked). RunnerSpace may also enable Members to publicly display some Registration PII as an element of their Profile Information if they choose to do so via a profile setting under “Edit Details.” Search engines may index the portion of a Member’s profile (including the Profile Information it contains) that is publicly displayed.

If you have consented to receive promotional materials (e.g., newsletters) or notifications from RunnerSpace, RunnerSpace may periodically use your email address to send you such materials related to the RunnerSpace Services, as applicable. If you want to stop receiving such materials from RunnerSpace, you can change your profile settings under "Notifications / Privacy Settings" //www.runnerspace.com/forum/index.php?app=core&module=usercp&tab=core&area=notifications or follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

RunnerSpace employees, agents and contractors must have a business reason to obtain access to your PII. RunnerSpace may share your PII with those who help us manage or provide RunnerSpace Services’ information activities (for example, message, team, contest administration, customer service, order fulfillment, statistical analyses, data processing), or with outside contractors, agents or sponsors who help us with the administration, judging and prize fulfillment aspects of contests, promotions and sweepstakes.

RunnerSpace member accounts are secured by member-created passwords RunnerSpace.com takes precautions to insure that member account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect member information that is stored within our database. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of member information at any time although it is very unlikely.

These outside contractors, agents or sponsors may temporarily store some information on their servers, but they may only use your PII to provide RunnerSpace with a specific service and not for any other purpose. RunnerSpace may also provide your PII to a third party in those instances where you have chosen to receive certain information and have been notified that the fulfillment of such a request requires the sharing of your PII. RunnerSpace also may share your PII with Affiliated Companies if it has a business reason to do so.

As described in “Notice” above, RunnerSpace may customize the advertising and marketing messages you receive on the RunnerSpace Website, or may work with outside companies to do so. Your non-PII and/or Profile Information may be shared with these companies so this customization can be accomplished. RunnerSpace prohibits these companies from sharing your non-PII and/or Profile Information with any third party or from using it for any other purpose. Anonymous click stream, number of page views calculated by pixel tags, and aggregated demographic information may also be shared with RunnerSpace’s advertisers and business partners.

There may be instances when RunnerSpace may access or disclose PII, Profile Information or non-PII without providing you a choice in order to: (i) protect or defend the legal rights or property of RunnerSpace, our Affiliated Companies or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements); (ii) protect the safety and security of Users of the RunnerSpace Services or members of the public including acting in urgent circumstances; (iii) protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or (iv) comply with the law or legal process. In addition, if RunnerSpace sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of all or a material part of its assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or transfer of all or a material part of its business, RunnerSpace may transfer your PII to the party or parties involved in the transaction as part of that transaction.

When a Member who is located in the European Union chooses to post Profile Information that will be publicly disclosed, that Member is responsible for ensuring that such information conforms to all local data protection laws. RunnerSpace is not responsible under the EU local data protection laws for Member-posted information.

SECURITY: RUNNERSPACE PROTECTS THE SECURITY OF PII

RunnerSpace uses commercially reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard PII and credit card information in its possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. In addition, RunnerSpace uses reasonable methods to make sure that PII is accurate, up-to-date and appropriately complete.

INVITATIONS AND OTHER COMMUNICATIONS TO NON-MEMBERS OR VISITORS

RunnerSpace members can invite friends to join the service by sending invitation emails via our automated invitation system or Facebook invites via our Facebook api. RunnerSpace stores the email addresses that members provide so that the respondents may be added to the friend's list of the member sending the invitations, and also to stop them sending further invitations. RunnerSpace does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations, invitation reminders. Recipients of invitations from RunnerSpace may contact RunnerSpace to request the removal of their information from our database.

ACCESS, REMEDIES AND COMPLIANCE: HOW TO ACCESS, CORRECT OR CHANGE YOUR PREFERENCES REGARDING YOUR PII AND HOW TO CONTACT RUNNERSPACE ABOUT PRIVACY CONCERNS

Whenever possible, RunnerSpace Members may review the Registration PII we maintain about them in our records. We will take reasonable steps to correct any PII a Member informs us is incorrect. If you are a Member, you can view and change your Registration PII, Member preferences and Profile Information by logging into your account and accessing features such as “Edit Details” and "Notifications / Privacy Settings" //www.runnerspace.com/forum/index.php?app=core&module=usercp&tab=core&area=notifications .

If you ask RunnerSpace to stop using your PII, RunnerSpace will honor that request while retaining any record of your PII that is necessary to comply with applicable federal, state or local law.

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post public information to Blogs, Walls, Messages etc or any other Public Forums that that information can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications

If you would like to communicate with us about this Privacy Policy or RunnerSpace’s collection and use of your PII, please use the Contact info below.

RunnerSpace  
P.O. Box 10984  
Eugene, OR 97440  
contact@runnerspace.com
